export const questionsData = [
  {
    question:
      'Which cells in the retina are responsible for vision in dim light?',
    answers: ['Cone cells', 'Rod cells', 'Ganglion cells', 'Amacrine cells'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Where are cone cells primarily concentrated in the retina?',
    answers: ['Periphery', 'Fovea', 'Optic disc', 'Vitreous humor'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which type of cone detects short wavelengths of light?',
    answers: ['Protan', 'Deutran', 'Tritan', 'Rod cells'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is rhodopsin?',
    answers: [
      'A pigment in cone cells',
      'A light-sensitive pigment in rod cells',
      'A structural protein in the sclera',
      'A vitamin essential for retinal development',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which layer of the retina contains the axons of ganglion cells?',
    answers: [
      'Inner nuclear layer',
      'Outer nuclear layer',
      'Retinal nerve fiber layer',
      'Photoreceptor layer',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the main function of the retinal pigment epithelium (RPE)?',
    answers: [
      'Blood supply to the retina',
      'Recycling retinal pigments and supporting photoreceptor cells',
      'Transmitting electrical signals to the brain',
      'Absorbing excess light entering the eye',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the central depression in the macula called?',
    answers: ['Perifovea', 'Parafovea', 'Fovea', 'Umbo'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which dietary components are associated with reducing the risk of diabetic retinopathy?',
    answers: [
      'Retinol and vitamin D',
      'Lutein and zeaxanthin',
      'Omega-3 fatty acids',
      'Calcium and magnesium',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What embryonic structure gives rise to the retina?',
    answers: [
      'Neural crest',
      'Optic vesicle',
      'Mesenchymal tissue',
      'Optic fissure',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which artery primarily supplies the inner layers of the retina?',
    answers: [
      'Central retinal artery',
      'Long posterior ciliary artery',
      'Choroid',
      'Ophthalmic artery',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question: 'What causes the blind spot in the visual field?',
    answers: [
      'Absence of cones in the periphery',
      'Absence of photoreceptor cells at the optic disc',
      'Damage to the retinal nerve fiber layer',
      'Lack of blood supply to the macula',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which refractive error increases the risk of retinal detachment?',
    answers: ['Hyperopia', 'Myopia', 'Astigmatism', 'Presbyopia'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary pathology in retinitis pigmentosa?',
    answers: [
      'Loss of ganglion cells',
      'Gradual loss of rods and cones',
      'Retinal ischemia due to vascular occlusion',
      'Overgrowth of retinal blood vessels',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which layer of the retina contains synapses between bipolar cells and ganglion cells?',
    answers: [
      'Outer nuclear layer',
      'Inner plexiform layer',
      'Outer plexiform layer',
      'Inner limiting membrane',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the hallmark finding in central retinal artery occlusion (CRAO)?',
    answers: [
      'Pigment deposits in the retina',
      'Cherry-red spot on the macula',
      'Leakage of fluid from blood vessels',
      'Detachment of retinal layers',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the most common type of age-related macular degeneration?',
    answers: [
      'Neovascular AMD',
      'Wet AMD',
      'Non-neovascular AMD',
      'Central serous AMD',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What characterizes closed-angle glaucoma?',
    answers: [
      'Increased intraocular pressure due to blocked iridocorneal angle',
      'Degeneration of photoreceptor cells',
      'Loss of the blood-retinal barrier',
      'Fluid leakage into the subretinal space',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the most common intraocular complication in patients with HIV?',
    answers: [
      'Retinoblastoma',
      'Cytomegalovirus retinitis',
      'Diabetic retinopathy',
      'Retinopathy of prematurity',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the leading cause of blindness among adults under 75 in developed countries?',
    answers: [
      'Age-related macular degeneration',
      'Retinitis pigmentosa',
      'Diabetic retinopathy',
      'Glaucoma',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary role of the retina in the eye?',
    answers: [
      'Adjusting the lens for focusing',
      'Transmitting and focusing light',
      'Receiving and processing light signals',
      'Maintaining intraocular pressure',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which structure is responsible for focusing light onto the retina?',
    answers: ['Cornea', 'Iris', 'Lens', 'Choroid'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What type of vision are rod cells primarily responsible for?',
    answers: [
      'Photopic vision',
      'Scotopic vision',
      'Color vision',
      'Peripheral vision',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the approximate number of cone cells in the human retina?',
    answers: ['6 million', '90 million', '15 to 20 million', '3 million'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the term used to describe the absence of photoreceptor cells at the optic nerve site?',
    answers: ['Fovea', 'Cone mosaic', 'Blind spot', 'Rhodopsin'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which photopigment is found in rod cells?',
    answers: ['Photopsin', 'Rhodopsin', 'Melanopsin', 'Scotopsin'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary cause of glaucoma?',
    answers: [
      'Genetic mutations',
      'Overproduction or impaired drainage of aqueous humor',
      'Irregular curvature of the cornea',
      'Inherited autosomal recessive genes',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What type of visual impairment is characterized by 'tunnel vision'?",
    answers: [
      'Achromatopsia',
      'Retinitis pigmentosa',
      'Diabetic retinopathy',
      'Glaucoma',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which gene is associated with the photopigment rhodopsin?',
    answers: ['Chromosome 3', 'Chromosome 7', 'X chromosome', 'Chromosome 15'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which cells are responsible for color vision?',
    answers: ['Rods', 'Cones', 'Retinal ganglion cells', 'Bipolar cells'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the function of melanopsin in the retina?',
    answers: [
      'Color vision',
      'Night vision',
      'Regulation of circadian rhythms',
      'Focusing light onto the retina',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What condition describes the irregular curvature of the cornea or lens?',
    answers: ['Myopia', 'Hyperopia', 'Astigmatism', 'Glaucoma'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which type of cone photopigment is sensitive to short wavelengths?',
    answers: ['L-cones', 'M-cones', 'S-cones', 'Photopsin I'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary cause of diabetic retinopathy?',
    answers: [
      'Overaccumulation of glucose damaging blood vessels and neurons',
      'Genetic mutations affecting rod cells',
      'Buildup of drusen and lipofuscin',
      'Increased intraocular pressure',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which component of the phototransduction pathway inhibits cGMP-dependent cation channels?',
    answers: [
      'Rhodopsin kinase',
      'cGMP phosphodiesterase',
      'Arrestin',
      'Guanylyl cyclase',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which photopigment gene is located on the X chromosome?',
    answers: ['S-cones', 'Rhodopsin', 'M-cones and L-cones', 'Melanopsin'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the role of retinal horizontal cells?',
    answers: [
      'Transmit signals to the optic nerve',
      'Inhibit photoreceptor neurotransmitter release',
      'Absorb light and generate action potentials',
      'Adjust the lens for focusing',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the absorption maxima for photopsin III?',
    answers: [
      'Yellowish-green light',
      'Green light',
      'Bluish-violet light',
      'Red light',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which disease is characterized by the degeneration of the macula?',
    answers: [
      'Retinitis pigmentosa',
      'Age-related macular degeneration (AMD)',
      'Diabetic retinopathy',
      'Glaucoma',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What does 'bleaching' in photoreceptors refer to?",
    answers: [
      'The activation of cGMP phosphodiesterase',
      'The absorption of a photon by a pigment molecule',
      'The isomerization of retinal to its active form',
      'The restoration of cGMP levels',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following is NOT an application of OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Real-time 3D imaging',
      'Cellular-level spatial resolution',
      'Long-range sonar detection',
      'Non-invasive medical diagnostics',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What type of waves does OCT use for imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Sonic waves',
      'Electromagnetic waves',
      'Gamma rays',
      'Neutron waves',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the primary principle behind Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT)?',
    answers: [
      'Ultrasound Imaging',
      'Low Coherence Interferometry',
      'High Coherence Spectroscopy',
      'Doppler Effect',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the typical resolution range of OCT?',
    answers: ['10-100 µm', '1-15 µm', '20-30 µm', '5-50 µm'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What type of scan is created by repeatedly performing A-scans while varying the reference mirror position?',
    answers: ['C-scan', 'B-scan', 'M-scan', 'D-scan'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which of the following is the first clinical application of OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Cardiovascular diseases',
      'Eye diseases such as glaucoma',
      'Skin imaging',
      'Neurological imaging',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'In an OCT system, what determines the tissue thickness?',
    answers: [
      'Light intensity',
      'Optical delay and speed of light in the tissue',
      'Wavelength of light',
      'Beam focusing conditions',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which technology uses a moving reference mirror for image acquisition?',
    answers: ['SD-OCT', 'TD-OCT', 'SS-OCT', 'FD-OCT'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is a key disadvantage of TD-OCT compared to FD-OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Lower axial resolution',
      'Slower image acquisition speed',
      'Limited depth penetration',
      'Complex system design',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which OCT technique replaces the detector with a spectrograph for simultaneous frequency analysis?',
    answers: ['TD-OCT', 'SD-OCT', 'SS-OCT', 'PS-OCT'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the main advantage of SS-OCT over SD-OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Lower cost',
      'Longer wavelengths for deeper penetration',
      'Simultaneous frequency detection',
      'Higher axial resolution',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What determines the axial resolution of an OCT system?',
    answers: [
      'Beam focusing conditions',
      'Coherence length of the source',
      'Detector sensitivity',
      'Light wavelength',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary source of noise in OCT systems?',
    answers: [
      'Photon noise',
      'Thermal noise',
      'Electrical interference',
      'Acoustic vibrations',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What type of noise in OCT degrades image quality by reducing contrast?',
    answers: [
      'Photon noise',
      'Speckle noise',
      'Dark current noise',
      'Thermal noise',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What does Doppler OCT measure?',
    answers: [
      'Tissue stiffness',
      'Fluid flow velocity',
      'Light polarization',
      'Tissue thickness',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary clinical use of PS-OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Imaging blood flow',
      'Analyzing tissue polarization properties',
      'Measuring tissue stiffness',
      'Depth penetration imaging',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which OCT method uses the Doppler effect for its measurements?',
    answers: ['PS-OCT', 'Doppler OCT', 'Elastography OCT', 'SS-OCT'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the term 'dynamic range' refer to in an OCT system?",
    answers: [
      'Sensitivity of the detector',
      'Ratio of maximum to minimum measurable values',
      'Range of wavelengths used',
      'Resolution of the system',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following is NOT a source of noise in OCT systems?',
    answers: [
      'Photon pressure',
      'Mechanical vibrations',
      'Thermal fluctuations',
      'Optical fiber alignment',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is measured in OCT elastography?',
    answers: [
      'Blood flow velocity',
      'Tissue birefringence',
      'Mechanical properties of tissue',
      'Depth penetration of light',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the unit of dynamic range in OCT systems?',
    answers: ['Hertz', 'Micrometers', 'Decibels', 'Watts'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which OCT technique is not yet commercially available due to high costs?',
    answers: ['TD-OCT', 'SD-OCT', 'SS-OCT', 'Doppler OCT'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'When did OCT achieve its first significant application in ophthalmology?',
    answers: ['1970s', '1980s', '1990s', '2000s'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which property of OCT allows it to achieve high spatial resolution?',
    answers: [
      'Use of non-ionizing radiation',
      'Low coherence interference',
      'High-frequency X-rays',
      'Magnetic resonance principles',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the speed of electromagnetic waves in a vacuum?',
    answers: ['3 x 10^6 m/s', '3 x 10^8 m/s', '3 x 10^12 m/s', '3 x 10^14 m/s'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What phenomenon occurs when two electromagnetic waves interact?',
    answers: ['Diffraction', 'Interference', 'Refraction', 'Dispersion'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What determines the refractive index of a material?',
    answers: [
      'Wavelength and amplitude',
      'Speed of light in vacuum and in the medium',
      'Frequency and phase',
      'Absorption and scattering',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the formula relating wavelength (λ) and frequency (f) in electromagnetic waves?',
    answers: ['c = λ * f', 'c = λ / f', 'c = f / λ', 'c = λ^2 * f'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which tissue property most significantly affects OCT imaging depth?',
    answers: [
      'Absorption coefficient',
      'Refractive index',
      'Magnetic properties',
      'Electrical conductivity',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the main function of an interferometer in OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Generate electromagnetic waves',
      'Measure the intensity of backscattered radiation',
      'Produce ultrasound waves',
      'Detect gamma radiation',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the spectral range referred to as the 'therapeutic window' in OCT?",
    answers: [
      '250 nm - 600 nm',
      '600 nm - 1200 nm',
      '1200 nm - 2000 nm',
      '2000 nm - 3000 nm',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which scattering type dominates in dense, organized media?',
    answers: [
      'Rayleigh scattering',
      'Mie scattering',
      'Diffuse scattering',
      'Inelastic scattering',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary advantage of OCT compared to ultrasound?',
    answers: [
      'Use of sonic waves',
      'Higher imaging depth',
      'Real-time 3D imaging',
      'Use of ionizing radiation',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What happens to light when it encounters a discontinuity in the medium?',
    answers: [
      'It stops propagating',
      'It is completely absorbed',
      'It is reflected and refracted',
      'It changes its frequency',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which law explains the refraction of light between two media?',
    answers: [
      'Lambert-Beer law',
      "Snell's law",
      "Planck's law",
      'Doppler effect',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What type of scattering is characterized by photons interacting with atoms smaller than the wavelength of light?',
    answers: [
      'Mie scattering',
      'Rayleigh scattering',
      'Inelastic scattering',
      'Forward scattering',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following factors does NOT affect OCT imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Wavelength of the source',
      'Magnetic properties of tissue',
      'Composition of the sample',
      'Refractive index mismatch',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the significance of the near-infrared window in OCT?',
    answers: [
      'It reduces the cost of imaging',
      'It allows for better penetration depth',
      'It enhances magnetic field interactions',
      'It avoids diffraction effects',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the purpose of using different wavelengths in OCT imaging?',
    answers: [
      'To increase imaging speed',
      'To improve image resolution',
      'To optimize imaging for different tissue types',
      'To reduce interference patterns',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the primary advantage of OCT in medical imaging?',
    answers: [
      'It uses X-rays',
      'It is non-invasive',
      'It requires anesthesia',
      'It is expensive',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What type of data does OCT provide?',
    answers: [
      'Quantitative only',
      'Morphological only',
      'Both morphological and quantitative',
      'Neither morphological nor quantitative',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the typical penetration depth of OCT in gastrointestinal tissues?',
    answers: ['0.5-1.0 mm', '1.2-1.6 mm', '2.0-2.5 mm', '3.0-4.0 mm'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'In which medical field is OCT most widely used?',
    answers: ['Dermatology', 'Cardiology', 'Ophthalmology', 'Dentistry'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What does high reflectivity in an OCT image indicate in retinal tissue?',
    answers: [
      'Healthy tissue',
      'Scar tissue or atrophy',
      'Fluid accumulation',
      'Transparent areas',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What can OCT detect in the anterior segment of the eye?',
    answers: [
      'Blood clots',
      'Corneal infections',
      'Iris volume and thickness',
      'Tumors',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question: 'What feature is observed in OCT images of retinal detachment?',
    answers: [
      'Increased reflectivity',
      'Optically empty spaces',
      'Irregular vessel walls',
      'Rounded hypo reflective areas',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'Which type of eye surgery uses OCT for precision?',
    answers: [
      'Cataract surgery',
      'PRK and LASIK',
      'Vitrectomy',
      'Glaucoma surgery',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What distinguishes red blood clots in OCT imaging?',
    answers: [
      'High reflectivity',
      'Low reflectivity',
      'Strong backscatter',
      'Transparent appearance',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is a characteristic of fibrous lesions in OCT cardiovascular imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Hyporeflective areas',
      'High backscatter and homogeneity',
      'Transparent appearance',
      'Irregular shapes',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'How does OCT help in assessing atherosclerosis?',
    answers: [
      'By measuring nerve thickness',
      'By analyzing vessel wall damage',
      'By detecting retinal detachment',
      'By measuring tumor sizes',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What morphological change is observed in malignant melanoma using OCT?',
    answers: [
      'Visible basement membrane',
      'Loss of basement membrane zone',
      'High reflectivity of dermis',
      'Uniform epithelial stratification',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which cancer shows hypo-reflective rounded areas in OCT imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Lung cancer',
      'Basal cell carcinoma',
      'Oral cancer',
      'Prostate cancer',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'How does OCT identify squamous cell carcinoma in lung cancer?',
    answers: [
      'Dark, spherical structures',
      'Bright, irregular signals',
      'Transparent masses',
      'Uniform cell layers',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What feature is seen in OCT imaging of breast cancer?',
    answers: [
      'Homogeneous cell distribution',
      'Loss of normal structures and asteroid schematic lesions',
      'Transparent areas surrounded by normal tissue',
      'Regular fibrous trabeculae',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'How are cancerous lymph nodes identified in OCT imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Uniform backscatter',
      'High heterogeneity with hole-like structures',
      'Low reflectivity areas',
      'Smooth, rounded structures',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the main diagnostic limitation of OCT in cancer imaging?',
    answers: [
      'Low resolution',
      'Inability to distinguish benign from malignant tumors',
      'High cost',
      'Requirement for anaesthesia',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What application does PS-OCT have in dentistry?',
    answers: [
      'Imaging dental tubules',
      'Diagnosing gingivitis',
      'Measuring bone density',
      'Visualizing dental caries',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which OCT application is particularly useful in detecting pulmonary hypertension?',
    answers: [
      'Measuring iris thickness',
      'Identifying fibrous lesions in vessels',
      'Imaging cartilage degeneration',
      'Detecting intraretinal cysts',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question: 'What is a primary disadvantage of OCT mentioned in the text?',
    answers: [
      'Use of ionizing radiation',
      'Dependence on high-quality sources',
      'Limited imaging resolution',
      'Invasive procedure',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      'Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT) is a preferred diagnostic tool for detecting which of the following retinal conditions?',
    answers: [
      'Diabetic retinopathy',
      'Retinitis pigmentosa',
      'Macular edema',
      'Conjunctivitis',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the diagnosis of diabetic macular edema (DME), OCT is used primarily to assess:',
    answers: [
      'Retinal blood vessel leakage',
      'The presence of retinal hemorrhages',
      'Macular thickness and fluid accumulation',
      'Vitreous detachment',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
];
